Asian Arts Medium Format Photograph Collection
Yale University Arts Library
Asian Arts Medium Format Photograph Collection
1900-2005
VRC 11
Yale University Arts Library
17.4
11 boxes
Collection of medium format mounted black and white and color reproductions of Asian arts. Content varies from original photographic prints to reproductions from magazines and other published sources. Some sections have accompanying clippings folders.
Conditions Governing Access
These materials are stored offsite at the Library Shelving Facility. For access to the materials, please make a request at the Art & Architecture Library.
Arrangement
Arranged by country or region. The country or region is further divided by medium and chronological period. Individual artists listed, if known.
Scope and Contents
Collection of medium format mounted black and white and color reproductions of Asian arts. Content varies from original photographic prints to reproductions from magazines and other published sources. Some sections have accompanying clippings folders.
Arts, Asian; Photographs; Reproductions
- Painting., 506
  - Central Asia., 1 (Box 1)
  - India., 7 (Box 1)
  - China., 398
    - Miscellaneous works., 6 (Box 1)
      - Six Dynasties., 2 (Box 1)
      - Liao Dynasty., 1 (Box 1)
      - XX Century., 3 (Box 1)
    - T'ang Dynasty., 96 (Box 1)
      - Miscellaneous works., 4 (Box 1)
      - Tomb of Prince Chang-Huai (Li Hsien)., 51 (Box 1)
      - Tomb of Prince I-Te (Li Chung-Jun), 706., 41 (Box 1)
    - Five Dynasties., 2 (Box 2)
      - Known artists., 2 (Box 2)
        - Shih K'o., 2 (Box 2)
    - Sung Dynasty., 153
      - Unknown artists., 42 (Box 2)
      - Known artists., 111
        - Miscellaneous artists, A-Z., 25 (Box 2)
          - Chang Ssu-Kang., 2 (Box 2)
          - Chao Ch'ang., 1 (Box 2)
          - Chao Meng-Chien., 1 (Box 2)
          - Chiang Ts'an., 1 (Box 2)
          - Chih-Weng., 1 (Box 2)
          - Han Jo-Cho., 1 (Box 2)
          - Kuo Hsi, c.1020-1090., 2 (Box 2)
          - Li T'ang, c. 1049-after 1130., 5 (Box 2)
          - Li Ti, c.1130-1200., 4 (Box 2)
          - Liang K'ai, c.1140-1210., 1 (Box 2)
          - Lu Hsin-Chung., 1 (Box 2)
          - Ma Kung-Hsien, active c.1131-1162., 1 (Box 2)
          - Mao I., 2 (Box 2)
          - Mao Sung., 1 (Box 2)
          - Yen Ts'u-Ping., 1 (Box 2)
        - Individual artists, A-Z., 86
          - Chao Ch'ang., 2 (Box 3)
          - Hsu Kuei, XII C., 10 (Box 3)
          - Hui-Tsung, 1082-1135., 8 (Box 3)
          - Kung Su-Jan. XII C., 5 (Box 3)
          - Li Ch'ueh, XIII C., 4 (Box 3)
          - Lo Chu'ang., 3 (Box 3)
          - Ma Lin, -after 1246, 4 (Box 3)
          - Ma Yuan, active c.1190-1224., 14 (Box 3)
          - Mu-Ch'i., 16 (Box 4)
          - P'u-Yueh., 5 (Box 4)
          - Sung Ju-Chih, active c.1260., 3 (Box 4)
          - Yu Chien, active mid-XIII C., 6 (Box 4)
          - Yu Tzu-Ming., 6 (Box 4)
    - Yuan Dynasty., 35 (Box 4)
      - Unknown artists., 3 (Box 4)
      - Known artists., 32 (Box 4)
        - Miscellaneous artists., 16 (Box 4)
          - Chao Meng-Fu, 1254-1322., 2 (Box 4)
          - Chao Yuan., 1 (Box 4)
          - Chao Yung, 1298-., 3 (Box 4)
          - I-An., 2 (Box 4)
          - P'u Ming, mid-XIV C., 2 (Box 4)
          - Wang Meng, 1308-1385., 4 (Box 4)
          - Wu T'ai-Su, XIV C., 2 (Box 4)
        - Individual artists, A-Z., 16 (Box 4)
          - Ch'ien Hsuan, 1235-1300., 8 (Box 4)
          - Yen Hui, mid-XIV C., 8 (Box 4)
    - Ming Dynasty., 33 (Box 5)
      - Unknown artists., 1 (Box 5)
      - Known artists., 32 (Box 5)
        - Miscellaneous artists, A-Z., 32 (Box 5)
          - Chao Che, XVI C., 4 (Box 5)
          - Ch'iu Ying, XVI C., 10 (Box 5)
          - Kuan Hsiu., 4 (Box 5)
          - Kuo Hsu, 1456-1526., 1 (Box 5)
          - Pien Wen-Chin., 3 (Box 5)
          - Shang Hsi., 2 (Box 5)
          - Shen Chou, 1427-1509., 2 (Box 5)
          - T'ang Yin, 1460-1524., 1 (Box 5)
          - Tung Ch'i-Ch'ang, 1555-1636., 2 (Box 5)
          - Yang Wen-Ts'ung, 1597-1645., 2 (Box 5)
    - Ch'ing Dynasty., 73
      - Known artists., 73
        - Miscellaneous artists, A-Z., 12 (Box 5)
          - I Hai., 3 (Box 5)
          - Kao Ch'i P'ei, 1672-1734., 1 (Box 5)
          - Kung Hsien, active 1656-1682., 1 (Box 5)
          - Lo Mu, 1622-after 1706., 1 (Box 5)
          - Lu Yuan, XVII C., 1 (Box 5)
          - Ma Yuan-Yu, 1669-1722., 1 (Box 5)
          - T'ang I-Fen, 1778-1853., 1 (Box 5)
          - Wang Hui, 1632-1717., 1 (Box 5)
          - Wang Wu, 1632-1690., 2 (Box 5)
        - Individual artists, A-Z., 61 (Box 6)
          - Hua Yen, 1682-1765., 5 (Box 6)
          - K'un Ts'an, XVII C., 3 (Box 6)
          - Lang Shih-Ning, 1688-1766., 10 (Box 6)
          - Li Shan, active 1710-1760., 6 (Box 6)
          - Pa-Ta-Shan-Jen, 1625-after 1705., 24 (Box 6)
          - Shih-T'ao, 1641-c.1720., 13 (Box 6)
  - Japan., 107
    - Late Yamato, 552-710., 4 (Box 7)
      - Unknown artists., 3 (Box 7)
      - Known artists., 1 (Box 7)
        - Kanoka, Kose No, VII C., 1 (Box 7)
    - Nara Period, 710-794., 9 (Box 7)
      - Unknown artists., 7 (Box 7)
      - Known artists., 2 (Box 7)
        - Mitsunaga, Kasuga No., 1 (Box 7)
        - Sodzu, Yeshin., 1 (Box 7)
    - Kamakura Period, 1185-1336., 7 (Box 7)
      - Unknown artists., 4 (Box 7)
      - Known artists., 3 (Box 7)
        - Keion, Sumiyoshi., 1 (Box 7)
        - Mitsushige, Tosa., 1 (Box 7)
        - Nobuzane, Fujiwara No, 1176-1265., 1 (Box 7)
    - Muromachi Period, 1336-1573., 21 (Box 7)
      - Unknown artists., 4 (Box 7)
      - Known artists., 17 (Box 7)
        - Chokuan, Soga, active 1596-1610., 1 (Box 7)
        - Densu, Cho, 1352-1431., 1 (Box 7)
        - Do-an, Yamada, -1571., 1 (Box 7)
        - Masanobu, Kano, 1453-1550., 1 (Box 7)
        - Motonobu, Kano, 1476-1559., 2 (Box 7)
        - Noami, 1397-1471., 1 (Box 7)
        - Sesshu Toyo, 1420-1506., 3 (Box 7)
        - Sesson, 1504-c.1589., 1 (Box 7)
        - Shibun (of Sokokuji)., 1 (Box 7)
        - Shibun, Soga, late XIV C., 1 (Box 7)
        - Soami, c.1485-1525., 1 (Box 7)
        - Shubun, Tensho, active c.1400-1450., 1 (Box 7)
        - Sotan, Oguri, early XV C., 1 (Box 7)
        - Yogetsu, XVI C., 1 (Box 7)
    - Momoyama Period, 1573-1615., 25 (Box 8)
      - Unknown artists., 7 (Box 8)
      - Known artists., 18 (Box 8)
        - Ko-I, Kano, 1566-1636., 1 (Box 8)
        - Mitsunobu, Kano, 1565-1608., 1 (Box 8)
        - Naizen, Kano, 1570-1616., 1 (Box 8)
        - Naonubu, Kano, 1607-1651., 1 (Box 8)
        - Sanraku, Kano, 1559-1635., 3 (Box 8)
        - Sansetsu, Kano, 1589-1651., 1 (Box 8)
        - Sotatsu, Tawaraya, 1576-1643., 3 (Box 8)
        - Tanyu, Kano, 1602-1674., 2 (Box 8)
        - Togan, Unkoku, active 1573-1591., 1 (Box 8)
        - To-un, Kano, XVII C., 1 (Box 8)
        - Yeitoku, Kano, 1543-1590., 2 (Box 8)
        - Yusho, Kaihoku, 1533-1615., 1 (Box 8)
    - Edo Period, 1615-1867., 40 (Box 9)
      - Unknown artists., 10 (Box 9)
      - Known artists., 3 (Box 9)
        - Buson, Yosa, 1716-1783., 3 (Box 9)
        - Fukaye, Roshu, 1699-1755., 1 (Box 9)
        - Gyokudo, Uragami, 1754-1820., 1 (Box 9)
        - Hiroshige, Ando, 1797-1858., 3 (Box 9)
        - Hyakusen, Sakaki, 1698-1753., 1 (Box 9)
        - Itcho, Hanabusa, 1652-1724., 1 (Box 9)
        - Kiitsu, Suzuki, 1796-1858., 2 (Box 9)
        - Korin, Ogata, 1658-1716., 1 (Box 9)
        - Kyosai, Kawanabe, 1831-1889., 1 (Box 9)
        - Matabe, Iwasa, 1578-1650., 1 (Box 9)
        - Morikage, Kusumi, c.1620-1690., 1 (Box 9)
        - Musashi, Miyamoto, 1548-1645., 1 (Box 9)
        - Ritsuo, Ogawa, 1689-1747., 1 (Box 9)
        - Sengai, Gibon, 1750-1837., 4 (Box 9)
        - Taiga, Ikeno, 1723-1776., 3 (Box 9)
        - Tanyu, Kano, 1602-1674., 1 (Box 9)
        - Totsugen, Tanaka, -1823., 1 (Box 9)
        - Tsunenobu, Kano, 1636-1713., 1 (Box 9)
        - Yasunobu, Kano, 1613-1685., 1 (Box 9)
        - Yukinobu, Kiyohara, 1643-1682., 1 (Box 9)
    - Meiji Period., 1 (Box 9)
      - Known artists., 1 (Box 9)
        - Mitsuoki, Tosi, 1917-1991., 1 (Box 9)
- Architecture., 55
  - Miscellaneous countries., 6 (Box 10)
    Scope and Contents
    Includes a folder of miscellaneous clippings.
    - China., 1 (Box 10)
      - Man-Ch'eng., 1 (Box 10)
    - India., 3 (Box 10)
      - Madura., 1 (Box 10)
      - Mount Abu., 1 (Box 10)
      - Sanchi., 1 (Box 10)
    - Thailand (Siam)., 2 (Box 10)
      - Bangkok., 2 (Box 10)
  - Individual countries., 49
    - Cambodia., 23 (Box 10)
      - Angkor Thom., 6 (Box 10)
      - Angkor Wat., 17 (Box 10)
    - Japan., 21 (Box 10)
      - Himeji., 1 (Box 10)
      - Ise, Mie Prefecture., 2 (Box 10)
      - Izumo, Shimane Prefecture., 1 (Box 10)
      - Kotohira., 1 (Box 10)
      - Kyoto., 2 (Box 10)
      - Nara., 9 (Box 10)
      - Nikko., 2 (Box 10)
      - Uji., 3 (Box 10)
    - Java., 5 (Box 11)
      - Boro-Bodur., 5 (Box 11)
- Sculpture., 18 (Box 11)
  - Miscellaneous countries., 5 (Box 11)
    - Burma (Myanmar)., 1 (Box 11)
    - India., 2 (Box 11)
    - Japan., 2 (Box 11)
  - Individual countries., 13 (Box 11)
    - Cambodia., 8 (Box 11)
    - China., 5 (Box 11)
- Minor Arts., 10 (Box 11)
  - Ceramics., 1 (Box 11)
    - China, Ming Dynasty., 1 (Box 11)
  - Jade., 2 (Box 11)
    - China, 2 (Box 11)
  - Lacquer., 1 (Box 11)
    - China, Sung Dynasty., 1 (Box 11)
  - Metal., 1 (Box 11)
    - China, Western Han., 1 (Box 11)
  - Prints., 4 (Box 11)
    - China, XVII C., 1 (Box 11)
    - Japan., 3 (Box 11)
      - Unknown artists., 1 (Box 11)
      - Known artists., 2 (Box 11)
        - Utamaro, Kitagawa, 1754-1806., 1 (Box 11)
        - Wang-Wu., 1 (Box 11)
  - Textiles., 1 (Box 11)
    - China., 1 (Box 11)